Guide to the Historic newspapers, 1789-2001.
Historic newspapers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Historic newspapers, 1789-2001.
8496
0.4 cubic feet.
Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Issues of historic American newspapers.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Issues of historic American newspapers.
SUBJECTS
Form and Genre Terms:
Newspapers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- The New-York Journal, and Weekly Register, March 5, 1789; Rudin # H-1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  The First Congress Convenes- First printing of the announcement of the opening of Congress
- The New York Tribune, April 16, 1861; Rudin # H-2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Headlines: "War Begun", "The Bombardment of Fort Sumter", "The Fort in Flames"
- Daily Evening Traveller, March 12, 1862; Rudin # H-3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Monitor vs Merrimac, front page and page two
- The Courier, April 29, 1862; Rudin # H-4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Monitor vs Merrimac, printed on peach color adversity paper
- Daily Evening Traveller, July 3, 1863; Rudin # H-5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Front page headline regarding battle of Gettysburg
- The New York Times, April 5, 1865; Rudin # H-6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Front page concerns events from the final days of the Civil War
- Boston Daily Advertiser, April 11, 1865; Rudin # H-7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Civil War Ends- General Lee Surrenders
- New York Tribune, October 10, 1871; Rudin # H-8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  "Chicago in Ashes"- The great Chicago Fire, with front page map
- The Omaha Daily Bee, April 16, 1912; Rudin # H-9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  "Titanic Sinks: 1200 Persons Reported to be Lost"
- The Florida Times-Union, April 3, 1917; Rudin # H-10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  World War I Begins- "President Asks Congress for Declaration of a state of war
- The Pittsburgh Post, November 11, 1918; Rudin # H-11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  World War I Ends- "War is Over- Truce is signed"
- The Denver Post, December 8, 1941; Rudin # H-12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  World War II Begins - "War Declared on Japan"
- Los Angeles Times, June 6, 1944; Rudin # H-13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  "Invasion" allied landings begin in France, with front page map. Includes a New York Times ad supplement
- The Baltimore News Post, June 8, 1944; Rudin # H-14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  "First Phase of Invasion Battle Won"
- The Philadelphia Inquirer, August 15, 1945; Rudin # H-15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  World War II ends- "Peace: Truman Announces Jap Surrender"
- The Louisville Times, August 15, 1945; Rudin # H-15A (Box 1, Folder 15)
  World War II Ends- "MacArthur orders Japs to Manila"
- The New York Times, July 21, 1969; Rudin # H-16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  "Men Walk on Moon", with special commemorative supplement. Also includes a special edition of Life Magazine and a full mint sheet of Moon Landing 10 cent stamp
- The New York Times, October 20, 1987; Rudin # H-17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  "Stocks plunge 508 points, a drop of 22.6%: 604 million volume nearly doubles record"
- The New York Times, September 12, 2001; Rudin # H-18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  "Hijacked Jets Destroy Twin Towers..." with special issue of Time Magazine regarding the Twin Tower attack